&gt；&gt；Kyle：词法范围，这就是我们一直在讨论的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Lexical scope, that's what we've been talking about,
我们现在要给它起个正式的名字。
we're gonna give it that formal name now.
这就是它所指的，作用域相互嵌套的想法。
That is what it is referred to, this idea of scopes being nested within each other.
具体地说，编译器、解析器、处理器正在解决所有问题
And specifically the idea that a compiler, a parser, a processor is figuring out all
这些作用域在被执行之前提前，
those scopes ahead of time before being executed,
这就是我们所说的词汇范围的概念。
that's what we mean by the concept of lexical scopes.
这就是那个名字的来历
That's where that name even comes from,
lex与解析的第一阶段lexa共享相同的根。
that lex shares the same root as the first stage of parsing, the lexa.
所以想想词汇范围，当你听到这个术语时，就认为它是相关的
So think of lexical scope, when you hear that term, think of that as related
对编译器来说，本质上与作者的时间决定有关。
to the compiler, related to, in essence, the author time decision.
或者是我在作者时代做出的将这个函数放在这个函数中的决定
Or it's the decision I made at author time to put this function inside of this one
这个变量最终会变成大理石颜色。
and have this variable that's gonna end up being this marble color.
它是在编译时决定的。
It's decided at compile time.
它不是在运行时决定的，它不会以任何方式、形状或
It's not decided at run time, it is not affected in any way, shape, or
根据程序中发生的情况形成。
form by what happens in the program.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这是第一个，我认为绝对是最主要的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: That is the first, and I would argue definitely the most predominant,
编程语言之间作用域的模型。
model for scoping among programming languages.
事实上，绝大多数现有的编程语言，以及
In fact, the vast majority of all programming languages in existence, and
几乎可以肯定你曾经使用过的所有编程语言，
almost certainly all programming languages that you've ever worked with,
实际上是词汇范围的。
are in fact lexically scoped.
当人们说JavaScript不是词汇范围时，有时会让我感到恼火
Bugs me sometimes when people say JavaScript isn't lexically scoped
因为JavaScript行为的一些细微差别。
because of some of the nuances of JavaScript's behavior.
它是绝对的，100%的词汇范围。
It is absolutely, definitely, 100% lexically scoped.
毫无疑问。
There's no question about it.
然而，还有另一种作用域模型。
There is, however, another model for scoping.
这是不是很常见，你通常只看到这一点
It is not very common at all, you generally only see this in
一些古老的学术语言，也许还有一些不同的模式。
a few old academic languages and maybe some different modes.
可能是动态作用域模型最主要的示例
Probably the most predominant example of the dynamic scoping model
实际上是Bash脚本。
is actually Bash script.
如果您在Bash中做过大量的脚本编写工作，
If you've done any significant amount of scripting in Bash,
它实际上是动态作用域，而不是词法作用域。
it is actually dynamically scoped rather than lexical scoped.
这与我们之前的直觉有点吻合，即Bash脚本是
And that fits a bit with our intuition earlier that Bash script is
这些解释语言中的一种，它不是那些编译语言中的一种。
one of those interpreted languages, it's not one of those compiled languages.
所以它没有编译时间是有意义的
So it sort of makes sense that it doesn't have a compile time
作用域模型，因为它没有编译，好吗？
scoping model since it's not compiled, okay?
所以我们的直觉是吻合的。
So there's a match in our intuition there.
所以让我们确保我们有一个强有力的定义，或者
So let's make sure we put a strong definition, or
围绕这个词汇范围有一个很强的想法。
a strong idea around this lexical scope.
我们头脑中的直觉是，当我们考虑词汇范围时，
The intuition in our head is that when we think about lexical scope,
我们思考一些在作者时间固定的东西
we think about something that is fixed at author time and
它是可预测的，不受运行时条件的影响。
it's predictable, it is not affected by run time conditions.
动态范围这个名称意味着相反的意思，对吗？
The name dynamic scope implies the opposite, right?
它意味着运行时条件，程序的动态条件，
It implies that the run time conditions, the dynamic conditions of your program,
将影响范围的某些方面。
are going to affect something about the scoping.